# Gerald (Jerry) Ryle

jerry@ryle.io +1 (650) 400-9551 jerryryle.com

I am an engineering leader with a strong software engineering background and a breadth of experience in product development that includes device software, cloud software, and mobile apps. I build and lead teams that plan and execute well. I work cross-functionally and with all levels of leadership to meet our business objectives while shipping products that our customers love.

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Verily Life Sciences**, South San Francisco, CA **Head of Medical Devices Software**, 2019-2022

- Led teams of **embedded**, **mobile**, and **cloud** developers that created the software that runs Verily's highly-integrated medical devices, connects them to the cloud, and ingests/processes their data for various applications
- Brought three significant cloud-connected hardware and software products from early development to shipping:
  - · Verily Retinal Camera camera that uses AI for low-cost, high-quality detection of diabetic retinopathy
  - Verily Patch adhesive patch and **mobile app** that regularly measures an individual's body temperature
  - Verily Study Watch sensor-packed, wearable device and mobile app for continuous, non-invasive monitoring
- Kept my organization lean and productive amidst shifting company priorities; helped plan and execute initiatives to better align Verily's hardware investment with company strategy

# Fresh Health, Inc., Mountain View, CA

## **V.P. Engineering**, 2017-2018

- Hired and led a cross-functional team of engineers and consultants to build a revolutionary consumer health device
- Produced our pivotal patent application, which helped secure us a funding round of \$30M
- Bootstrapped the company: set up payroll and benefits, hired development partners, created interview process, defined peer review and feedback process, codified development methodology, and set engineering goals

# Mindtribe Product Engineering, San Francisco, CA Partner and V.P. Engineering, 2001-2017

- Built Mindtribe into a 40-person, world-class engineering consultancy that was acquired by Accenture
  - Redesigned our engineering methodology to improve outcomes, which differentiated Mindtribe's services and led
    to larger and more interesting contracts
  - Brought Agile values to hardware engineering, enabling rapid product development
  - Responsible for business development, sales, program management, process development, strategy, hiring, engineering leadership, and technical execution
  - Helped numerous startups scale their technologies and their teams from MVP to mass-market
  - Select projects:

#### Stealth Company, Encrypted Communications Device, 2015-2016

- Led a cross-functional team to take a complex, consumer electronics device for encrypted voice communications from concept through manufacturing in less than a year
- Solved technical challenges relating to security, testability, and manufacturability

#### Adobe, Project Parallel, 2012

- Led a team of **mobile** developers and designers to create Line, Adobe's Ink and Slide showcase app
- Taught Adobe's other app teams the **Agile**, rapid development methodology that we used on Line

#### Square, Stand, 2012

- Led a cross-functional team to deliver Stand, Square's point-of sale solution for brick-and-mortar retailers
- Structured and ran this program from concept through manufacturing
- · Set clear priorities for the team, which allowed us go from concept to shipping product in less than a year

#### **EDUCATION**

California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, CA | B.S., Computer Engineering, Class of 2000

#### **PATENTS**

<u>US11234801B2</u>, <u>US9262777B2</u>, <u>US9286635B2</u>, <u>US9495676B2</u>, <u>WO2012177370A1</u>